Hello, and welcome back. It's time now to present examples of
【未完成版本】大家好 欢迎回来 现在到了展示图像处理中稀疏建模例子的时候了
sparse modeling in image processing. Before we do that, we have to do one more
在这之前 我们还得干件事
thing. Now, remember what we have.
回忆一下我们学习了什么
We have a dictionary of K elements, K atoms, and every atom has N dimensions.
我们有一个K列的字典 K个原子 每个原子是N维的
Now, what are basically the, basically the signals that we are going to process?
现在 我们要处理的信号是什么呢？
And that's what we need to discuss just for one minute.
我们需要花点时间来讨论它
And the basic idea is very simple. We're going to be talking about images.
基本思路很简单 我们要来讨论图像
This is going to be our data, the noisy image.
y是我们的数据 即有噪声的图像
The whole image. This is what we are looking for.
一整张图像 x就是我们想要寻找的
Now, we are not going to work on entire images,
现在 我们并不是要处理整张图片
we are going to work on patches. And this is the r.
而是分块 (patches) 处理 这是R
The r is just a basic, a simple binary matrix that extracts the patch around ij.
R表示在(i,j)处提取图像块的二元矩阵
So, if we have an image, for every pixel, we construct a patch around it.
所以 在一幅图像中 对每一个像素 我们在它四周构建一个块
Or, we could actually consider ij the upper left corner.
或者 我们也可以考虑(i,j)位于块的左上角
Anything that is good as a coordinate system, and we extract patches.
坐标系的选取可以是任意的 然后我们提取出块
For example, eight by eight patches as we have been talking.
比如说 之前谈论过的8x8的块
Now, it's very important that we do not take blocks as we did on JPEG, in JPEG.
现在我们选取块的方法跟JPEG中的方法有所不同 这一点很重要
We actually take all the patches that are fully overlapping.
在这里 我们选取的块都是重叠的
So, we have an image, and we take a patch, and we take the
所以 对一张图片 我们选取一个块
patch next to it and the patch next to it.
然后我们选取旁边的块 再选取旁边的块
So, for every pixel, let's say the upper left corner,
对每一个像素 假定它位于块的左上角
we construct the eight by eight patch. So, this is a binary matrix that extracts
我们构建一个8x8的块 这个二元矩阵能够提取出这个块
that patch. And it's the patch that we want to have a sparse code for it with a
对于这个块 我们使用学习好的字典来获得它的稀疏编码
learned dictionary. So here is the sparsity.
这是稀疏度
So, we're not working on the whole image at once, we're working on all the
所以我们不是立刻处理整张图像 而是处理
overlapping patches of the image. And, what we have is as we discussed
这幅图像中所有重叠的块 这个是我们以前讨论过的
before, the model is for the individual patches.
针对单个块的模型
We're going to construct a dictionary that works, for example, on all the
我们要构造一个字典 比如说
overlapping patches of a given image at the same time.
能够同时处理给定图像的所有重叠块
And note here, we are doing basically the optimization over the signal, this is the
注意这里 我们是要对信号做优化
whole image. We are looking for the sparse code,
这表示整个图像 我们要找到稀疏编码
this is the second part. And as we're going to see in a second,
这是第二个部分 过会我们将会看到
we're also going to learn the dictionary. We could learn the dictionary offline or
我们也要学习字典 我们可以离线学习字典
we could learn it and adopt it for the image as we're going to explain.
或先学习然后使它适应于图像 我们会马上讲解它
Once again, this is just nothing than a binary measure that extracts the patch.
再提一下 这仅仅是一个提取块的二元矩阵
So think like you have the image, you pick a patch,
所以想象你有一幅图像 然后选取一个块
you do sparse coding. You pick the next patch,
对它做稀疏编码 然后选取下一个块
Now, what about then the dictionary?
再做稀疏编码 现在字典是怎么得到呢？
The first option is to train on a large database.
第一种方法是由一个数据库训练得到
So, you do that offline you train on a large database.
你可以离线做这个 由一个数据库训练得到
The second option, and these are not contradictory as we're going to see in a
第二种方法 和我们就要看到的没有什么不同
second, is to use the image itself. You travel all around the patches of the
就是使用图像本身 遍历这幅图像所有的块
image, that gives you a lot of training data already.
而这已经给了我们很多的训练数据
And the basic idea is that normally we combine both of them.
基本的思路是 一般我们会结合这两种方法
That's one possibility. So, you learn a dictionary with a bunch
这是一种可能 所以 我们可以通过一堆现成的图像来离线学习字典
of images off the shelf offline, and that you use as your initialization of the
然后将此作为K-SVD所用字典的初始值
dictionary for K-SVD, and then you get the new image.
然后我们针对新的图像
Even though it's noisy, you adapt the dictionary to the image.
尽管它有噪声 我们调整字典来适应图像
So, you run a few iterations of this dictionary adaptation, K-SVD, sparse
对于特定的某幅图像迭代运行字典适应、K-SVD、稀疏编码
coding, dictionary adaptation, sparse coding for the particular image.
字典适应、稀疏编码
That's one option. The other is to forget completely about
这是一种选择 另一种就是完全忘记这些
this and start with any visualization and only run it here.
然后从任意的字典开始 并且只在这幅图像中学习字典
So, there is many options and, depending on the application, which one you can
所以 我们有很多选择 但要根据应用来选择
pick. Now, if you are in a rush and you don't
如果很急的话
have computational time to do the de-noising, you don't have to update the
也没有运行去噪算法的时间 我们可以不必更新字典
dictionary. Basically, you train it with a database.
可以用一个数据库来训练字典
Let's say, that you want to do faces, you train it with a database of faces and you
比方说 你要处理人脸 你可以用人脸数据库来训练字典
use that dictionary. If you have computational time to do
然后你就可以使用这个字典 如果你有计算时间
that, it's always better to basically adapt the dictionary to the particular
使字典适应于特定的图像 这总是要好些的
image. And we have tons of data for that because
我们有一堆的数据来做这个
we can use all the patches for doing that.
因为我们可以使用图像中所有的块
So, once again, this is our general formulation but now we have D either
再说一遍 这就是一般化的公式 现在D也加入进来了
because we are starting from scratch for the particular image or because we are
因为D是我们从特定的图像中学习得到的
adopting the pre-learned dictionary to the current image.
或者我们需要调整预先学习好的字典 来适应当前的图片
We have to, this is our data. And we have to, basically reconstruct the
这是我们的数据 我们必须重建这幅图像
image, we have to compute the code, we have to compute the common dictionary,
必须计算编码 必须计算共同的字典
one dictionary for all the patches in the image.
一个用于图像中所有块的字典
We are not allowed to use a dictionary per patch,
我们不允许每个块使用不同的字典
that would be basically ridiculous. So, we have three things to optimize for
这很荒谬 所以 我们需要优化三个参数
and the basic idea is very simple. You fix two, you optimize for the third
基本思路很简单 先将其中两个固定 再优化第三个
one. For example, you fix,
比如说
you ignore x and basically you assume that x is fixed.
忽略x 假设x是不变的
So you ignore this term, and you fix D, and you do sparse coding.
忽略这一项 再固定D 然后做稀疏编码
That counts the first part of K-SVD. Then, you fix the code,
这是K-SVD的第一个部分 接下来 固定这个编码
and you update the dictionary. And this is basically an iteration that's
更新字典 这是一个迭代的过程 即K-SVD
basically K-SVD. So, you have the image, you go over the
所以 对一幅图像 仔细检查每一个块
patches. Every patch becomes the columns of the
每个块都作为矩阵x的列
large x matrix that we saw in the previous video.
矩阵x我们在前一个视频里见过
And then you do K-SVD for all of them, okay?
然后你对所有这些做K-SVD 懂了吗？
So you are encoding with sparse coding every patch.
对每一个块用稀疏编码方法编码
When you're finished, you update the dictionary, you encode again, you update
完成编码后 就更新字典 接着又一遍的编码 再更新字典
the dictionary. When you are done with the dictionary,
当你完成了字典的计算
all that's left is to compute x. So, you basically don't touch the code
剩下的就只有计算x了 所以 你不用再计算编码了
anymore, don't touch the dictionary anymore.
也不用再更新字典了
And you have to basically solve for this problem when basically D and alpha are
当D和α都已经固定时 你就可以解决这个问题了
already fixed. Of course, this is gone.
当然 这个约束条件没了
x only shows up here and shows up here, and is very easy to show that the result
x只在这里和这里出现 很容易得出
is basically the weighted average of the patches.
结果就是块的加权平均
So what happened is that every pixel is touched by multiple patches.
我们知道 每个像素被多个块所覆盖
So let me just draw that here, for example.
让我在这里画出来 比如说
We have an image, and we have a pixel.
有一幅图像 这是一个像素点
Now, there are multiple patches that touch that pixel.
现在 有多个块覆盖那个像素点
For example, this one that has the picture kind of the, pixel, kind of the,
比如说 这个块的左底部角落覆盖了像素点
on the bottom left corner. There is also this one.
这个块也覆盖了像素点
basically there is also let me just use the different color, there is for
让我用不同的颜色标记一下
example, a patch here. There is how many?
这个块也是 那么 一共有多少个块呢？
If we have eight by eight, we have 64 patches that are touching that pixel,
如果是块的大小是8x8的话 我们就有64个块覆盖那个像素
unless the pixel is at the border of the image.
除非这个像素是在图像的边界
Let's ignore those for a second. And basically, for everyone of those
我们先忽略这些边界的像素 对于这些块
patches, we have sparse coding with the dictionary that we have learned from all
我们使用之前的字典对它们做稀疏编码 这个字典
the patches in the image. So, that sparse coding, basically for
是从图像的所有块中学习得来的 对于每一个块
every single one of these patches is that we can reconstruct it as the alpha with
计算它们的稀疏编码 我们可以用Dα来重建这些块
the optimal alpha that we have compute for every single of the patches ij.
这里的α是针对每一个块ij 计算出的最优值
Every single one has been reconstructed. How do we reconstruct the pixel?
每一个块都被重建了 那如何重建这个像素呢？
We basically average all those patches. You can add weights to the average.
我们取所有块的平均值 也可以做加权平均
What's basically what the theory tells you.
这个定理告诉了你如何做加权平均
If it's, the pixel is in the center of the patch, then that patch is more
如果像素点在块的中间 那么 这个块就
important than if the pixel is in the corner of the patch, but that's just a
比像素点在角落的块要更重要
technicality. You can basically just do the
但这仅仅是个技巧 你也可以重建每个块
reconstruction of every patch with the sparse code and the dictionary that we
运用稀疏编码和学习好的字典
have learned and just average those 64 if you're using an eight by eight block.
如果块的大小是8x8的话 你可以仅仅对这64个块取平均
So now, this is all what you do. Every patch sparse coding and K-SVD to
你需要做的就是这些 对每个块做稀疏编码 运用K-SVD来学习字典
learn the dictionary. So, I think we are ready now to see
现在 我认为我们已经做好看例子的准备了
examples. Let's start from a image in gray values,
让我们从一幅非彩色的灰色图像开始
no color. This is the source image, and this is a
这是源图像
noisy image. We have add, we have added Gaussian noise
这是带噪声的图像 我们加了高斯噪声
with these variants. Now, we can initialize the dictionary
噪声方差为20 我们可以从这幅图像中
with random patches from this image. We don't have this image anymore.
随机选取块来初始化字典 我们不再有这幅图像
This is just for reference. This is all what we have.
这只是做个参照 这才是我们所拥有的图像
We can initialize with patches from here. We can initialize with a dictionary that
我们可以用这里的块来初始化 也可以用离线学习好的字典来初始化
we have learned offline, or we can initialize with something that
或者我们也可以其他不错的值来初始化字典
we know is good, Discrete Cosine Transform Dictionary.
离线余弦变换的字典
That's the one used in JPEG. So we know it's reasonable a good
那是用在JPEG中的字典 我们知道这是一个很棒的算法
algorithm. So a, a good dictionary.
这个字典也很好
In this case, we have initialized with that.
在这个例子中 我们用它来初始化字典
And basically, we update using all the patches here all the possible patches.
然后用图像中所有的块 所有可能的块来更新字典
We learn the dictionary, then we encode every part with the
学习字典 然后利用学好的字典 运用稀疏编码来编码每个块
learned dictionary using sparse coding. Then, we average all the patches that
接着 对所有覆盖该像素点的块求平均
touch a given pixel. And voila, this is the dictionary that we
瞧 这就是我们学习好的字典
have learned. Very interesting how it has changed from
【未完成版本】从DCT字典转化到它的过程是很有意思的
the [UNKNOWN] dictionary. And here is the restored image where we
这是一张通过这两个过程降噪恢复出来的图片
basically have reduced the noise by two things, one projecting every patch to the
其中一个是利用稀疏编码将块投影到字典空间上
space defined by these dictionary using sparse coding, and then averaging the
然后对这些块求平均
purges. And here you have a result.
然后我们就得到了结果
This was the original, this is what's available to us, and this is the de-noise
这个是原始图像 这个是我们拿到的有噪声的图像 这个是降噪了的图像
data. Very important that the adaptation of the
很重要的一点是
dictionary is down with the noisy data and still the results are really, really
字典的适应性因为噪声数据有所下降 但是结果
good. And I want you, once again, to observe
仍然非常好 我希望大家再观察一下
the type of dictionary that we have learned from the image.
从图像中学习到的这个字典的类型
For example, it has learned that texture that we have here, the different types of
例如 它学习到了这里的这些纹理
texture, are learned in the dictionary. It was basically adapted to the image.
这个字典学习到了很多不同种类的纹理 它已经根据图像做出了调整
Now, how do we deal with color? There are numerous ways of dealing with
那么现在我们看看如何处理颜色 其实有非常多的方法可以处理颜色
color, but basically one of the simplest ways is to, instead of doing eight by
其中一个最简单的方法是 我们用 8 x 8 小片 x 3
eight patches, we do eight by eight by three.
来替代单一的 8 x 8 的小片
We could have done every color independently, as we have done for
我们可以对每个颜色分量单独处理
example, for in painting or even for compression.
就如我们在图像修复或者压缩里做的一样
But we can also take eight by eight by three patches.
但是我们也可以用 8 x 8 x 3 的小片来做这个
You know, we concatinate all the colors and we do K-SVD sparse modeling in
我们把所有的颜色拼起来 然后做完全一样的 K-SVD 稀疏建模
exactly the same fashion. Let's see some results. So, again, we
让我们来看看一些结果
always show the original just for reference because you never have it.
我们先看看原始图像 它只作为参考 因为我们实际上没有原始图像
What you have is this image, this is noisy image.
我们只有这个有噪音的图像
A noisy version of this. And then, you run K-SVD on this eight by
一个有噪音的版本 接着 我们运行 K-SVD
eight by three or five by five by three, depending on the patch size that you
大小的选择是 8 x 8 x 3 还是 5 x 5 x 3 则根据大家自己的决定
decide to use, and you get a very nice result of image
然后我们就会得到一个很好的图像降噪结果
denoising. And here are just the, basically, the
这里这个
standard measurements of, of p, K's and R in DB's to measure just the quality of
是对噪声测量的标准 用分贝(dB)表示结果的质量
the result. Here is another example.
这里是另一个例子
We start from again the reference. This is only for reference, the original
我们从参考图片开始 这只是个参考用的原始图片
image. We have noises.
这里有噪声
Look how bad it is. This is really bad.
图像质量非常差
We have added a lot of noise and we get a beautiful reconstruction from this sparse
我们添加了许多噪声 然后通过一个漂亮的稀疏表建模技术将其重建了
modelling technique. Really, really nice reconstruction with a
细节重建非常好
lot of details and a relatively high quantitative measurement.
测量结果也相对很高
Although, what's most important is the qualitative quality of the
当然最重要的还是重建的质量
reconstruction. So, we went from here to here.
我们从这里到这里
And once again, we learn the dictionary. In this case, we initialize a dictionary
再做一次字典学习 这个例子中
with an off the shelf pre-learned dictionary, and then we adapt it to this
我们用现成的预先学习的字典初始化字典
noisy image for a few iterations of K-SVD.
然后再将其用 K-SVD 对这张图片进行数次迭代 以适应这张噪声图片
Now, we can also do inpainting with this.
现在 我们就可以利用字典做图像恢复了
Inpainting is a particular example of noise where the noise is kind of so
图像修复是一个比较特别的噪声的例子 这种噪声
strong that it makes some pixels disappear. And, there's many ways of
非常强导致有的像素丢失了
defining the types of challenges of inpainting.
有许多方式可以定义图像修复这种类型的挑战
One of them is to take the image and to just drop 80% of the pixels.
其中一个是将图像中 80% 的像素丢弃
This is related to compressed sensing, and we're going to talk about that at the
这个也跟压缩感知有关 我们将在这周的最后一个视频里谈谈它
end of this week in just one video. we basically drop 80% of the pixels.
我们将 80% 的像素丢弃
You say, you're gone. So that's basically represented here with
我们说 好吧 像素没了 所以这些地方用黑色(0)来表示
dark values zero. So it's like, the noise is so strong that
这就好比噪声实在太强烈
you, basically there's nothing there. And then you run basically sparse
导致这里什么都没有 之后我们只需要在这张图片上
modelling and K-SVD starting with this image, this is the missing part.
运行稀疏表模型和 K-SVD 这些是丢失了的部分
We start from this image and here is the reconstruction.
我们从这张图像出发 然后这里是重建的结果
Once again, a very, very interesting result.
再一次地 我们得到了一个非常非常有趣的结果
We only had 20% of the pixels and we managed to do a nice reconstruction.
我们只有 20% 的像素 然后成功地得到了一个很好的图像重建
Again, we go from here to here. This is just for reference, this image.
再一次地 我们从这里到这里 这张图片只用作参考
Let's just see that in color. Again, 80% missing and here is the
我们来看看彩色的情况 同样是丢失了 80%
reconstruction. Once again, I think a very, very nice
这里是重建结果 还是一样 我觉得这是一个
result. Again, for this example, we started with
非常好的结果 对于这个例子 我们从
a dictionary that was learned from a database of natural images, then we adapt
一个已经从自然图像数据库学习过的字典出发
it to this image for a few iterations. And then, we do this by reconstructing
然后通过数次迭代使其与这张图片相适应
every patch and then averaging for every pixel all the patches that touch it.
最后对每一片都重建 并且对每一个像素 将与之邻接的小片平均 得到这个图像
Again, I think a very impressive result showing the power of this technique.
我觉得这是一个非常惊人的结果 它展示这个技术的强大之处
This is another example, instead of dropping the pixels, we do the same that
这是另一个例子 这次我们并不丢弃像素 我们对其
we did when we were talking about inpainting in general.
做的处理跟我们在讲图像恢复的时候一样
We write on top of the image, and then we do the reconstruction.
我们在图像表面写字 然后来做重建
Again, very good results with nothing else than doing sparse modeling, learning
同样 一个非常好的重建结果 可以用稀疏表建模
a dictionary from this noise image and being able to reconstruct this image.
和从这张噪声图像学习过的字典的方法来得到
Now, we can also do video inpainting. We can drop 80% of the pixels.
现在 我们还可以对视频做恢复 我们可以丢弃 80% 的像素
And now, again, we have a number of options.
现在 同样地 我们还有好几种不同的选择
We can do every frame by itself, or we can do patches in kind of three
我们可以一帧一帧地处理 或者我们也可以在X Y T这样的三维
dimensions, X, Y and T.
小片上做处理
We discussed about that when we were talking about video inpainting in the
我们在前几周讲解视频恢复的视频中已经讲述这些
previous week. Basically, we take patches, let's say, we
我们取一些小片 比如说
take three frames together, five frames together so the patches have also some
比如说三帧一起 五帧一起 那么小片就有了时序信息
temporal information. After we have decided what type of
当我们确定了使用那种小片之后
patches to use, we run sparse modeling with absolutely the same technique that
我们运行跟之前讲过的完全一样的稀疏表建模
we have been describing. And I'm going to run a few of them.
然后我将播放一下这个视频
The original is as always, only for reference.
原始的这个视频是拿来做参考的
It actually is not available. We always go from here to here doing the
实际上我们没有这个 我们是要从这里到这里来做字典学习
dictionary learning. Let me run a few frames.
让我来播放几帧看看
This is one frame, this is another frame. Look always at the quality of the result,
这是一帧 这又是一帧 请注意结果的质量
the reconstruction. Another one.
也就是重建的结果 另一帧
So once again, we basically walk through
又一帧 同样地 我们
the different frames going from this to this.
通过对每一帧都做从这个到这个处理
And you can always look at the reconstruction is very, very close to the
我们可以发现这个重建的结果
original that is not available to us. Just one more frame here.
跟这里这个我们不能获取的原始视频非常接近 这只是另一帧罢了
Now, I want to do an, yet another frame. I want to finish with demosaicing.
现在我想再讲讲下一张幻灯片 我想以去马赛克来结束本次视频
This would be the last example. It's kind of a particular case of image
这是最后一个例子 我们之前已经见过这种特殊类型的图像恢复
inpainting as we have seen before. Let me explain what's the problem here.
先让我解释一下问题在哪
Most digital cameras do not collect full red, green, and blue.
绝大多数照相机都没有完全收集红、绿、蓝的信息
They basically do a trick which is, one pixel, they collect ren, red.
它们玩了一个小技巧 一个像素只收集红色
The next, they collect green, the next, red, the next green, and so on.
下一个像素只手机绿色 然后红色 绿色 如此循环
For the next role, they collect green, blue, green, blue, green, blue, and then
对于下一行 它们收集 绿色 蓝色 绿色 蓝色
they repeat that. So, at every pixel, they have only one
如此循环 所以 对于每一个像素 它们只有一种颜色分量
color. Red, or green,
红的 绿的
or blue. And what you have to do is you have to
或者蓝的 我们要做的就是插值
interpret. In order to show me the image, you have
为了展现出图像
to, at every pixel, create a red degree and a blue.
我们必须对每一个像素 都重建出红色、绿色 和蓝色
This is kind of an interpretation or an inpainting of the colors.
这是一种插值 或者也是一种颜色修复
But, we can treat this as nothing esle than inpainting of the colors where
我们可以将这个问题看作颜色恢复
basically we have just, instead of dropping the entire pixel, we drop two of
不同于丢弃整个像素 这里是每个像素丢弃了
the colors of the pixel per pixel. Sometimes we draw up the red and the
两个颜色分量 有时候丢弃的是红色和绿色
green. Sometimes we draw up the green and the
有时候丢掉的是绿色和蓝色
blue. Sometimes we draw up the red and the
有时候丢掉的是红色和蓝色
So imagine that you have a queue which is
想象一下 我们有一个
n by n by three with sometimes is, you have it available and sometimes you
n x n x 3 的阵列 有时候里面有数据
don't. Now, we have seen that sparse modeling is
有时候没有 现在我们已经知道稀疏表建模
extremely successfully even when the entire pixel is gone.
对于整个像素都丢失的情况非常有效
Even when 80% of the complete pixels are gone.
即使 80% 的像素都完全丢失了
So, let's run it on this. And this is called demosaicing.
那么我们对这种图片来跑一下稀疏表建模 这也叫做去马赛克
It has to be done basically in all consumer digital cameras.
这个过程在所有消费数字照相机里都会出现
Very expensive digital cameras actually collect the full red, the full green, and
非常昂贵的数字照相机会真正地收集全部红色、全部绿色
the full blue. But, normal consumer cameras do this type of mosaic and then
以及全部蓝色 但是普通消费级相机 先收集这样的马赛克
the production of the full color image is called demosaicing. And here you see
然后通过去马赛克生成全彩图像
examples of color images that have been reconstructed from patterns like this
这里我们见到了一个用稀疏表建模 从这种模式
using sparse modeling. It's a particular case of basically
重建彩色图像的例子 这是一个彩色图像恢复中的特例
inpainting in the color domain. It's even easier than that, because
它比图像恢复更简单
instead of dropping entire 80% of the pixels, you just drop some of the colors
因为我们并非失去了 80% 的整个像素 我们的每一个像素只丢失了
per pixel, and the results are really, really nice results.
一些颜色通道 得到的结果当然非常非常好
We have, basically, some zooming, and you can see that the results are very, very
我们将其局部放大 然后可以看到这些结果非常非常好
sharp. And these are really some of the best
这些实际上是去马赛克中的最好结果之一
results produced with, for demosaicing. They're obtained with sparse modeling
它们是用稀疏表建模技术得到的
techniques. So, these are just some of the examples
这些只是稀疏表建模的一些例子
of sparse modeling. Sparse modeling in image processing is
最近几年 稀疏表建模在图像处理中
being used a lot these days, also for image classification and other image
使用得非常多 在图像分类和其他
processing challenges I have shown you for denoising, inpainting, demosaicing.
图像处理的挑战如去噪 恢复和去马赛克中也有使用
And I think that this basically illustrates the importance of the theory
我觉得这些已经展示出了这个
that has a lot of mathematical components.
有很多数学原理的理论的重要性
And basically also very, very cool applications.
还有这些很酷的应用
We have a couple of additional things to learn this week about sparse modeling and
这周我们还将学习稀疏表建模的一些东西
also about compressed sensing, and the connections between the two, and I am
还有关于压缩感知和这两者之间的联系
going to do that in the forth coming videos.
我将会在接下来的视频中讲解它们
Thank you very much, see you later.
谢谢大家 一会见【未完成版本】